Finding Aid for the The Papers of James Hampton Kirkland
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Personal/Biographical Material
  - Celebrating the 40th Year of Service of J.H. Kirkland (2) (Box 19, File 16)
  - Celebrating the 40th Year of Service of J.H. Kirkland (3) (Box 19, File 17)
  - Tributes to J. H. Kirkland – The 40th Anniversary, (an article)(1933) (Box 19, File 18)
  - Tributes to J. H. Kirkland – The 40th Anniversary (clippings)(1933) (Box 19, File 19)
  - Programs, The Memorial Service for J. H. Kirkland (1) (Box 19, File 20)
  - Programs, The Memorial Service for J. H. Kirkland (2) (Box 19, File 21)
  - Tributes in Memory of J. H. Kirkland (1) (Box 19, File 22)
  - Tributes in Memory of J. H. Kirkland (2) (Box 19, File 23)
  - Tributes in Memory of J. H. Kirkland (3) (Box 19, File 24)
  - Tributes in Memory of J. H. Kirkland (4) (Box 19, File 25)
- Personal/Biographical Material
  - Galluchat-Kirkland Families (1) (Box 20, File 1)
  - Galluchat-Kirkland Families (2) (Box 20, File 2)
  - Galluchat-Kirkland Families (3) (Box 20, File 3)
  - Galluchat-Kirkland Families (4) (Box 20, File 4)
  - Galluchat-Kirkland Families (5) (Box 20, File 5)
- Personal/Biographical - Academic Career
  - Academic Career: Grade book, 1887-1890 (Box 20, File 6)
  - Academic Career: Grade book, 1893-1903 (Box 20, File 7)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, 1884-85 (Box 20, File 8)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, 1884-85 (Box 20, File 9)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Greek and Latin (1) (Box 20, File 10)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Greek and Latin (2) (Box 20, File 11)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Greek and Latin (3) (Box 20, File 12)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Greek and Latin (4) (Box 20, File 13)
- Personal/Biographical Material - Academic Career
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Roman (1) (Box 21, File 1)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Roman (2) (Box 21, File 2)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Roman (3) (Box 21, File 3)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Roman (4) (Box 21, File 4)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Roman (5) (Box 21, File 5)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Roman (6) (Box 21, File 6)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Roman (7) (Box 21, File 7)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Roman (8) (Box 21, File 8)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, Roman (9) (Box 21, File 9)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, “The Study of Language” (Box 21, File 10)
  - Academic Career: Notebook, “ Miles Gloriousus” (Box 21, File 11)
- Personal/Biographical
  - Personal Collections: Personal Notes of Board of Trust Actions 1898-1910 (Three Notebooks) (Box 21, File 12)
  - Personal Collections: A Notebook (School Talks) (Box 21, File 13)
  - Personal Collections: A Notebook (Chapel Talks) (Box 21, File 14)
  - Personal Collections: A Notebook (Ladies Aid Notes) (Box 21, File 15)
  - Personal Collections: Extracts and Quotations – Prose (1) (Box 21, File 16)
  - Personal Collections: Extracts and Quotations – Prose (2) (Box 21, File 17)
  - Personal Collections: Extracts and Quotations – Verse (Box 21, File 18)
  - Personal Collections: “Southern Magazine” V. 5, Feb 1895 (Box 21, File 19)
  - Personal Collections: Confederate Money (Box 21, File 20)
  - Personal Collections: Residence of Chancellor J. H. Kirkland (Box 21, File 21)
  - Personal Collections: Invitations (Box 21, File 22)
  - Personal Collections: Photographs (1) (Box 21, File 23)
  - Personal Collections: Photographs (2) (Box 21, File 24)
  - Personal Collections: Certificates (Box 21, File 25)
- Personal/Biographical Material - Legal Documents
  - Deeds, 1852, 1861, 1877 (Box 22, File 1)
  - Deeds, 1881 (Box 22, File 2)
  - Deeds, 1882 (Box 22, File 3)
  - Deeds, 1883 (Box 22, File 4)
  - Deeds, 1884-1885 (Box 22, File 5)
  - Deeds, 1886-1887 (Box 22, File 6)
  - Deeds, 1888 (Box 22, File 7)
  - Deeds, 1889 (Box 22, File 8)
  - Deeds, 1890-1891 (Box 22, File 9)
  - Deeds, 1893, 1897, 1899 (Box 22, File 10)
  - Deeds, 1901, 1904-1907 (Box 22, File 11)
  - Deeds, 1920, 1924, 1925, 1938 (Box 22, File 12)
  - Will and Testament of Reuben Kirkland (Box 22, File 13)
  - Will and Testament of Joseph Galluchat (Box 22, File 14)
  - Field Notes (1) (Box 22, File 15)
  - Field Notes (2) (Box 22, File 16)
  - Burch Property -- Hillsboro Turnpike (Box 22, File 17)
  - Cornelius and William K. Vanderbilt Estates (Box 22, File 18)
  - Louis Moore Estates (Box 22, File 19)
  - W. A. Henderson Estate (Box 22, File 20)
  - Legal agreement between Vanderbilt University and George S. Wheat (Box 22, File 21)
- Personal/Biographical Material - Financial Records
  - Account Books (Box 23, File 1)
  - Bills (Box 23, File 2)
  - Bills (Box 23, File 3)
  - Received Checks (Box 23, File 4)
  - Receipts (Box 23, File 5)
  - Bonds (Box 23, File 6)
  - Stocks (Box 23, File 7)
  - Bell Fund Subscription, 1909 (Box 23, File 8)
  - Miscellaneous Materials (Box 23, File 9)
- Organizations and Institutions
  - Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools in the Southern States, 1915-1918 (programs, minutes, and reports) (Box 23, File 10)
  - Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools in the Southern States, 1837-38 (programs, minutes, and reports) (Box 23, File 11)
  - Southern Education Board, 1910-1914 (reports and minutes) (1) (Box 23, File 12)
  - Southern Education Board, 1910-1914 (reports and minutes) (2) (Box 23, File 13)
  - Conference on Education in the South, 1910-1914 (Box 23, File 14)
  - Southern University Conference, (1), 1935-1937 (Box 23, File 15)
  - Southern University Conference, (2), 1935-1937 (Box 23, File 16)
  - Southern University Conference, (3), 1935-1937 (Box 23, File 17)
  - National Conference Committee on Standards of Colleges and Second Schools, 1907-1913 (minutes) (Box 23, File 18)
  - American Council on Education (Box 23, File 19)
  - Vanderbilt University: College for Women (Box 23, File 20)
  - Vanderbilt University: Women’s Aid Society (1) (Box 23, File 21)
  - Vanderbilt University: Women’s Aid Society (2) (Box 23, File 22)
  - Vanderbilt University: Reports, Programs, and Handbooks (Box 23, File 23)
  - Varied Associations (1) (Box 23, File 24)
  - Varied Associations (2) (Box 23, File 25)
  - Programs of American Colleges (Box 23, File 26)
- Newspaper Clippings
  - The Daily American: “Vanderbilt University: An Institution of Which the South Is Proud”, July 14, 1886 (Box 24, File 1)
  - The Nashville American: “Alumni and Board of Trust -- Vanderbilt University’s Position in the Mooted Question,” by J. T. McGill, June 21, 1889 (Box 24, File 1)
  - Tennessee Methodist: “Vanderbilt University”, September 15, 1892 (Box 24, File 1)
  - Tennessee Methodist: “Correlation and Endowment -- An Address by Rev. J. J. Tigert, D.D.”, June 29, 1893 (Box 24, File 1)
  - Christian Advocate: “Letter from Judge Foote”, December 14, 1893 (Box 24, File 1)
  - 1895: “High School Improvement: The Subject is Discussed by Chancellor Kirkland”, March 26 (Box 24, File 1)
  - 1895: “The Board is Scored: Chancellor Kirkland, of Vanderbilt, Talks to their Heads, Discusses the High School”, March 26 (Box 24, File 1)
  - Christian Advocate: “Reminiscences of Dr. Garland,” by Charles F. Smith, March 28, 1895 (Box 24, File 1)
  - Christian Advocate: “Vanderbilt University”, September 19, 1895 (Box 24, File 1)
  - 1895: “Brilliant Nuptials: Miss Henderson Becomes the Bride of Chancellor Kirkland, of Vanderbilt University”, November 21 (Box 24, File 1)
  - Tennessee Methodist: “Religious Life at Vanderbilt University,” by W. B. Nance, 1895 (no date) (Box 24, File 1)
  - The Amateur Athlete: “Athletic Prosperity and Reform in the South,” by Caspar Whitney, 1896 (no date) (Box 24, File 1)
  - The Daily American: “Dr. John W. Boswell: Replies to Mr. Stokes’ Attack on Dr. Hoss”, June 19, 1897 (Box 24, File 1)
  - Arkansas Methodist: “Vanderbilt University,” by Sidney H. Babcock, July 21, 1897 (Box 24, File 1)
  - The Nashville American: “Famous Problem Solved: Most Interesting Contribution to the World’s Knowledge,” by J. C. Wharton, July 10, 1898 (Box 24, File 1)
  - The Nashville American: “Faculty’s Action is Announced”, April 20, 1901 (Box 24, File 1)
  - The Chicago Record-Herald: “Few Benefactions for Education in the South” May 15, 1902, Manufacturers’ Record: Quote from James H. Kirkland, April 30, 1902 (Box 24, File 1)
  - The Morning Post: “Correlation of Our Educational System. Address Delivered by President Mims of the North Carolina Teachers Assembly”, June 12, 1902 (Box 24, File 1)
  - St. Louis Christian Advocate: “On Being Alive Today,” by James W. Lee, June 13, 1902 (Box 24, File 1)
  - Christian Advocate: “A Passing Opportunity”, October 9, 1902 (Box 24, File 1)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “Vanderbilt correspondence”, October 9, 1902 (Box 24, File 1)
  - The Nashville American: “High Schools -- Idea of Their Work in Middle Tennessee”, October 10, 1902 (Box 24, File 1)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “Vanderbilt correspondence”, November 13, 1902 (Box 24, File 1)
  - The Nashville American: “The United States Leads”, January 2, 1903 (Box 24, File 2)
  - The Louisville Herald: “Just As It Ought To Be”, February 17, 1903 (Box 24, File 2)
  - Manufacturers’ Record: “Blind Leaders of the Blind”, February 19, 1903 (Box 24, File 2)
  - Christian Advocate: “The Recent Chicago Convention,” by H. M. Hamill, March 26, 1903 (Box 24, File 2)
  - Boston Evening Transcript: “Discipline in Education: President Butler’s Ideas on a College’s Mission,” by Nicholas M. Butler, March 28, 1903 (Box 24, File 2)
  - Christian Advocate: “Illiteracy in the South”, April 9, 1903 (Box 24, File 2)
  - Christian Advocate: “The Vanderbilt University School Conference,” by Joshua H. Harrison., May 14, 1903 (Box 24, File 2)
  - Manufacturers’ Record: “self-reliance in Southern Education”, May 5, 1904 (Box 24, File 2)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “Celebration of Dr. (James H.) Carlisle’s Birthday”, May 12, 1904 (Box 24, File 2)
  - 1904: “Vanderbilt Board of Trustees Meeting Called Thursday. Rumors of Chancellor Kirkland Going to U. T.”, June 21 (Box 24, File 2)
  - Christian Advocate: “Farewell Ode to Vanderbilt. Music by Mrs. E. L. Ashford. Words by Sadie Luff, ‘04”, July 7, 1904 (Box 24, File 2)
  - The Daily States: “Discouraging Philanthropy”, July 7, 1904 (Box 24, File 2)
  - The Churchman: “University Ideals at Sewanee”, July 9, 1904 (Box 24, File 2)
  - The Florida Christian Advocate: “Vanderbilt University,” by G. R. Mayfield, August 30, 1904 (Box 24, File 2)
  - 1904: “Formal Resignation: Dr. Alderman Writes to Tulane University”, July 7 (Box 24, File 2)
  - 1904: “An Important Decision” (J. C. Keener to Dr. Winton on Dartmouth College decision), October 17 (Box 24, File 2)
  - Christian Advocate: “Vanderbilt University -- Present Status,” by D. C. Kelley, March 9, 1905 (Box 24, File 3)
  - 1905: “Has Millions for Colleges: Andrew Carnegie Explains His Newest Plan of Benevolence”, March 30 (Box 24, File 3)
  - Christian Advocate: “ Bishop McTyeire and Vanderbilt University,” by D. C. Kelley, May 4, 1905 (Box 24, File 3)
  - The Nashville American: “Millions Given by Rockefeller for Education. Princely Endowment for Promotion of the Higher Branches”, July 1, 1905 (Box 24, File 3)
  - American Industries: “Our Cotton Trade in the Orient,” by John L. McLaurin, July 1, 1905 (Box 24, File 3)
  - Nashville Banner: “Vanderbilt University: Memorial Presented Tennessee Conference”, October 26, 1905 (Box 24, File 3)
  - Nashville Banner: “How Vanderbilt University came Into Existence”, November 28, 1905 (Box 24, File 3)
  - “Thirty years Ago -- Early History of Vanderbilt University”, 1905 (no date) (Box 24, File 3)
  - Birmingham News: “Church Asserts the Ownership: of Vanderbilt University and Charter Rights of Bishops”, May 10, 1906 (Box 24, File 3)
  - The Nashville American: “Vanderbilt University,” by D. C. Kelley, May 11, 1906 (Box 24, File 3)
  - Nashville Banner: “Dramatic Scene on the Conference Floor: Venerable Bishop Wilson Makes a Plea for Preservation of the Faith Which He Fears is Being Threatened,” by James B. Clark, May 12, 1906 (Box 24, File 3)
  - The Nashville American: “Vanderbilt University” (editorial), May 28, 1906 (Box 24, File 3)
  - The Nashville American: “Vanderbilt University,” by Bishop E. E. Hoss, June 1, 1906 (Box 24, File 3)
  - The Nashville American: “Vanderbilt University” (editorial), June 4, 1906 (Box 24, File 3)
  - The Nashville American: “Letter from Dr. Hoss,” by Bishop E. E. Hoss, August 10, 1906 (Box 24, File 3)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Vanderbilt University: Relations to the M. E. Church, South”, October 25, 1906 (Box 24, File 3)
  - Southern Christian Advocate: “The Vanderbilt Controversy,” by J. A. McCullough, November 8, 1906 (Box 24, File 3)
  - The Commercial Appeal: “Important Decision in the Vanderbilt University Case: Contention of Bishop Hoss and His Counsel, Albert W. Biggs, Sustained at Every Point”, December 10, 1906 (Box 24, File 3)
  - Pacific Methodist Advocate: “The Vanderbilt Controversy,” by J. A. McCullough, December 13, 1906 (Box 24, File 3)
  - New York Herald: “Inside Working of $43,000,000 Educational Trust Company: Millions of John D. Rockefeller have made the General Education Board a Corporation with practically Unlimited Influence and Power”, February 17, 1907 (Box 24, File 4)
  - The Nashville American: “Mecklenburg Declaration of Independence,” by Ainsworth R. Spofford, July 15, 1907 (Box 24, File 4)
  - Nashville Banner: “Vanderbilt University: Conference Cedes Rights and Authority,” by J. B. Clark, October 18, 1907 (Box 24, File 4)
  - The Commercial Appeal: “Vanderbilt Controversy Reopened at Springfield: Significance of Action of Tennessee Conference”, October 20, 1907 (Box 24, File 4)
  - The Nashville American: “Conference for Education -- Mr. Murphy Replies to Gov. Porter,” by Edgar Gardner Murphy, November 29, 1907 (Box 24, File 4)
  - Nashville Tennessean: “Board of Trade postpones Action: On Question of Inviting the Southern Education Conference to Meet Here”, December 6, 1907 (Box 24, File 4)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Surprise and Disappointment. Because of Additional Delay of Voting. Plan to Affiliate Vanderbilt and Peabody and Retirement of Chancellor Porter”, December 12, 1907 (Box 24, File 4)
  - The Nashville American: “Announcement Causes Comment: Plan for Affiliation of Schools Not Generally Known”, December 13, 1907 (Box 24, File 4)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Appropriation for Peabody: Chancellor Porter Confident of Securing Money”, December 14, 1907 (Box 24, File 4)
  - The Nashville American: “Chancellor Porter Denies Affiliation-- No Plan for Connection of Vanderbilt and Peabody Thought of”, December 15, 1907 (Box 24, File 4)
  - The Nashville American: “Bond Issue for Peabody College: Supreme Court may be Called to Pass on Acts”, December 19, 1907 (Box 24, File 4)
  - The Arkansas Gazette: “Reverend James Thomas Is Entirely Vindicated -- Thomas’ Answer to Bishop Hoss”, January 30, 1908 (Box 24, File 4)
  - Christian Advocate: “Furman Hall,” by H. F. Bailey, January 31, 1908 (Box 24, File 4)
  - The Advertiser: “Edgar Gardner Murphy”, February 20, 1908 (Box 24, File 4)
  - Christian Advocate: “An Educational Crisis,” by E. E. Hoss, April 24, 1908 (Box 24, File 4)
  - Atlanta Constitution: “Address of Dr. Pritchett to Methodist Educators”, May 21, 1908 (Box 24, File 4)
  - Christian Advocate: “Bishop McTyeire,” by Charles F. Smith, July 17, 1908 (Box 24, File 4)
  - The Nashville American: “Peabody Fund in Two More Months -- Board Will Meet in May”, March 29, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Constitution (Atlanta): “Re-nationalizing the South”, April 12, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Nashville Banner: “May Mean Much for Vanderbilt: Bill Passed in Lower House of Legislature”, April 22, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - 1909: “Church Opposes Carnegie Gift: Opposition Has Arisen to Bill Enabling Vanderbilt to Accept It”, April 23 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Nashville Tennessean: “Insidious Power of Education”, April 27, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Nashville Tennessean: “Vanderbilt Bill before Committee: Advantages and Disadvantages Are Discussed at Two Sessions”, April 28, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - Midland Methodist: “Vanderbilt Commencement”; “A Declined Communication” (“Church Ownership”), by H. M. Du Bose, June 23, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - Christian Advocate: “Church Ownership,” by E. E. Hoss, June 25, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - Christian Advocate: “Shall the Church lose Vanderbilt University?” by E. R. Hendrix, July 1, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Nashville American: “Wants Woodrow Wilson Chosen: Gov. Porter’s Selection for Peabody’s Head”, August 4, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Nashville American: “University of Nashville and University of Tennessee Joint Medical Department. The Consolidation of the Two Colleagues Most Important Recent Event in Southern Medical Education”, August 5, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Nashville American: “Vanderbilt and Peabody College for Teachers to Adjoin University”, August 8, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Peabody College for Teachers and Established Fact: Last Step Taken Yesterday and Plans Made Public – New Trustees Are Named”, August 8, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - Nashville Tennessean: “Peabody Fund Will Benefit Nashville: New School for Teachers Will Greatly Enhance Value of Property”, August 9, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - Nashville American: “Will be South of Vanderbilt -- Options Secure There for Greater Peabody”, August 9, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Vanderbilt and Peabody: New College to be Located Adjacent to the University”, August 9, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - Nashville Tennessean: “Disposition of Old University Campus”, August 10, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Closeness of Affiliation: Speculation as to Relationship between Vanderbilt and Peabody College”, August 10, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - Nashville American: “South Nashville Objects: Residents Feel as if Removal of Peabody is Unfair”, August 10, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - Nashville Tennessean: “Concerning Peabody College Corporation,” by Robert L. Morris; “That Vanderbilt -- Peabody Merger,” by H. M. DuBose, August 11, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Old University of Nashville Mother of Southern Schools,” by Dixon L. Merritt, August 28, 1909 (Box 24, File 5)
  - The Commercial Appeal: “Bishop Ward Nears Death”, September 10, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “Peabody and Vanderbilt – Further Light on the Subject which is Attracting State-Wide Notice,” by Baxter Smith, September 20, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “May Withhold Peabody Bonds. Squires Dislike Talk of Vanderbilt Affiliation”, October 5, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “Location of New Peabody -- Gov. Porter Says on Vanderbilt Campus”, October 11, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “Position of County Court: Grounds upon which It Made the Appropriation for Peabody College,” by E. R. Richardson, October 13, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Vanderbilt and Peabody College – Statement of Bishop Hoss on the Status and Relations of the University”, October 15, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “Vanderbilt -- Methodist Church -- Peabody Question,” by Robert L. Burch, October 17, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Vanderbilt -- Peabody Affair,” by E. E. Hoss, October 20, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Western Methodist: “Vanderbilt University (editorial); “Vanderbilt and the Church,” by G. B. Winton, October 21, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “Vanderbilt University,” by H. M. Hamill, October 21, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “Quotes the Commodore. “High Private” Toney Adds to the Vanderbilt Literature”, October 28, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “Money Will not be Disturbed – Litigation over Peabody Appropriation is Averted”, October 31, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Midland Methodist: “Vanderbilt Memorial (editorial), November 3, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “Peabody-Vanderbilt: Col. Smith Thinks the Community is Unduly Exercised over Million,” by Baxter Smith, November 11, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Texas Christian Advocate: “The Vanderbilt University Problem” (editorial), November 11, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “Hot Shot for South Side – Gov. Porter Quotes Bishop William Lawrence: Denies All Knowledge of Vanderbilt Merger”, November 15, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “Says his Scalp is Real Issue: Southern Methodist Lining Up for Bitter Struggle”, November 16, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville American: “New Peabody on Old Site. E. F. Turner, of Medical Faculty, Claims Information”, November 17, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Nashville Banner: “ The George Peabody College”, November 22, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - Midland Methodist: “Dr. Anderson and the Vanderbilt” (editorial), November 24, 1909 (Box 24, File 6)
  - The Epworth Era: “More ‘Tempest in a Teapot’”(editorial), December 2, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - Nashville Banner: “The General Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South,” by E. E. Hoss, December 4, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - Midland Methodist: “A Final Word” (editorial), December 8, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - Texas Christian Advocate: “The Vanderbilt University Controversy,” by G. B. Winton, December 9, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - Texas Christian Advocate: “The Vanderbilt-Peabody Affair,” by E. E. Hoss, December 9, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - Wesleyan Christian Advocate: “A Card from Chancellor Kirkland”, December 10, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “ Dr. Kirkland Vs Dr. DuBose”, December 15, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “Wants DuBose to ‘Fight Fair’. Ringing Card from Chancellor J. H. Kirkland”, December 16, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “Who Shall Run Vanderbilt: A Question Now Stirring the Methodist Church”, December 19, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “Peabody School for Teachers” (editorial), December 26, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “Peabody College and Vanderbilt University,” by G. N. Tillman, December 27, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Gov. Porter’s Letter to Peabody Fund Trustees”, December 28, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville Banner: “The Peabody College”(editorial), December 28, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “Looks Good for Peabody: Opposition in County Court is Disappearing”, December 28, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “Again, the Peabody”, December 28, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “ We Decline for Trustees”, December 28, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “J. E. Caldwell Comments on Two Recent Opinions about Peabody School”, December 28, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “Views of Judge Jas. C. Bradford on the Peabody School Matter,” by James C. Bradford, December 29, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “Prof. W. R. Webb Speaks Plainly: Nashville Ought to Have the Peabody Fund”, December 29, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville American: “Dazzled by a Million Dollars,” by J. M. Frost, December 30, 1909 (Box 24, File 7)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Management of Vanderbilt: Squire E. R. Richardson Predicts Change, Saying There Ought to be”, January 5, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)
  - The Nashville Banner: “Now or Never Says Bradford. If County Court Holds Bonds the Million May be Lost”, January 5, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)
  - Texas Christian Advocate: “Vanderbilt Once More,” by G. B. Winton; “The Reply of Bishop Hoss,” by E. E. Hoss, January 6, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)
  - The Nashville American: “The Peabody Matter”(editorial), January 6, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)
  - The Nashville American: “Court Acts on Peabody Bonds: By Vote of 22 to 20 It Decides to Postpone Delivery”, January 6, 1910 (Box 24, File 8)